Guide to the Frank Baker papers, 1641-2002 and undated, bulk 1740-1995 RL.00069
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings and Research Series, 1642, 1669, 1731-1797, 1922-1993 and undated, 48 boxes
  - Writings By Others Subseries, circa 1925-1995 and undated
    - Hardwick, Michael, Revolution in the Temple: Ben Sira and the Rise of the Aaronides, 1979 (Box 227)
    - Harper, Steve, Devotional Life in the Wesleyan Tradition: A Workbook, 1995 (Box 227)
    - Harrison, G. Elsie, Untitled essay on JW's letters, undated (Box 227)
    - Hart, Elizabeth, The Methodist Social Union and 'The Most Important Evening in Our History', 1990 (Box 227)
    - Hatcher, Stephen, The Origin and Expansion of Primitive Methodism in the Hull Circuit, 1819-1851, 1993 (Box 227)
    - Hawkins, Carol Luttrell John Wesley as the Editor of George Herbert's Poems, 1973 (Box 227)
      Master's thesis, University of Florida; advisor, Dr. T. Walter Herbert.
    - Hayes, Alan L., John Wesley, American Incendiary, 1979 (Box 228)
    - Heaton, John, The Oldest Methodist Chapel in the World, undated, and Wesley's Hymns, undated (Box 228)
    - Heizenrater, Richard, Each Page a 'Storehouse of Information', 1978 (Box 228)
    - Heizenrater, Richard, Introduction to Diary of an Oxford Methodist: Benjamin Ingram, 1733-1734, 1982-1983 (Box 228)
    - Held, Nancy J., The Political Views of John Wesley, 1976 (Box 228)
    - Higginson, Harry, Growing Up in East Hull, 1911-1929, 1992 (Box 228)
    - Holland, Lynwood, John Wesley and the American Revolution, 1963 (Box 228)
    - Holtmann, Jurgen, Hope and History, or: Theology as Eschatology, undated (Box 228)
    - Howard, Peter, Developments in the Itinerancy, 1933 (Box 228)
    - Hughes, Robert D., Wesleyan Roots of Christian Socialism, undated (Box 228)
    - Hynson, Leon, Creation and Grace in Wesley's Ethics, 1975 (Box 228)
    - Hynson, Leon, John Wesley and Political Reality, undated (Box 228)
    - Jackson, George, John Wesley as a Bookman, 1935 (Box 228)
    - Jennings, Theodore W., Wesley's Preferential Option for the Poor, undated (Box 228)
    - Johns, S.W., On First Reading John Wesley's Journal, 1930 (Box 228)
    - Jones, Marsh, 1994-1995 (Box 228)
    - Jones, W. Llewelyn, The Wesleys and Wales--Parts I and II, circa 1950 (Box 228)
    - Kallich, Martin, British Poetry and the American Revolution, 1988 (Box 228)
    - Kimbrough, S.T., Jr., Charles Wesley's Georgia Journal, 1996 (Box 228)
    - Klein, S. Paul, John Wesley, Practical Evangelist, 1979 (Box 228)
    - Kline, Lawrence, John Cotton: Apologist for The New England Way, 1966 (Box 228)
      Master's thesis, New York University.
    - Lawson, Rev. John, The Benevolent Neutral, 1978, 2 folders (Box 228)
      Unpublished autobiography of Lawson, former professor in the Candler School of Theology, Emory University, and co-editor of the Explanatory Works upon the New Testament unit of the Wesley Bicentennial Edition.
    - Levitt, Sister Nellie, Various poems and short pieces, undated (Box 229)
    - Little, Brooks Bivens ed., Methodist Union Catalog, 1967 (Box 229)
    - Macquiban, Tim, Wesley's Practice of Intrafaith Love, 1994 (Box 229)
    - Maser, Frederick E., two articles on Joseph Conrad 1957, 1991 and undated (Box 229)
    - Maser, Fred, Freedom of Speech in the History of Methodism, 1983 (Box 229)
    - Matthews, Terry, The Methodist Circuit-Rider: An American Religious and Social Institution on the frontier, undated (Box 229)
    - Meistad, Tore, Wesley's Theology of Salvation and Social Change, 1990 (Box 229)
    - Meistad, Tore, The Evolution of Methodist Theological Identity in Norway, undated (Box 229)
    - The Methodist Magazine, 1933-1938 (Box 229)
    - Melton, Gordon, John Wesley and the Supernatural, 1974 (Box 229)
    - Mercer, Jerry Lee, A Study of the Concept of Man in the Sermons of John Wesley, 1970 (Box 229)
      Table of contents and Chapter 1 of dissertation.
    - Myers, Robin, The Records of the Worshipful Company of Stationers and Newspaper Makers (1554-1912), 1983 (Box 229)
    - Newport, Kenneth, Charles Wesley's Interpretation of Some Biblical Prophecies According to a Previously Unpublished Letter Dated April 25, 1754, 1993 (Box 229)
    - Newton, John, Methodism and the Puritans, 1964 (Box 229)
    - Norwood, Frederick A., Historians' History: Rise of the United Methodist Commission on Archives and History, undated (Box 229)
    - Outler, Albert Cook, ed. John Wesley: [a representative collection of his writings], (1964) -- correspondence and drafts 1960-1963 and undated, folder 1 of 2 (Box 229)
    - Outler, Albert Cook, ed. John Wesley: [a representative collection of his writings], (1964) -- correspondence and drafts 1960-1963 and undated, folder 2 of 2 (Box 230)
    - Outler, Albert C., The Bicentennial and the Re-Invention of America, 1975 (Box 230)
    - Paschal, R. Wade Jr., Deuteronomy 32 in Jewish and Samaritan Traditions in Relation to John 17, undated (Box 230)
    - Peake, Arthur S., Lectures and Articles on Various Old and New Testament Topics, 1913-1928 and undated (Box 230)
    - Pitlard, Vickie, The Authenticity and Significance of Porneia in the Vice List Used in Romans 1:18-32, 1992 (Box 230)
    - Pollard, C. A Wesley Legacy, 1946 (Box 230)
    - Raitt, Jill, Feminine Symbols, Negative Evaluations, undated (Box 230)
    - Randolph, J. Ralph, John Wesley and the American Indian, 1971 (Box 230)
    - Rattenbury, John Ernest, Charles Wesley, Man and Verse, circa 1950, 1992, 2 folders (Box 230)
    - Rich, Robert, Water and Fire, 1988 (Box 230)
      A play: an account in six scenes of JW's ministry in Georgia, his return to England, his conversion in Aldersgate Street, and the beginnings of his life-long work of open-air preaching.
    - Rights, Douglas, "A Moravian's Report on John Wesley- 1737" undated (Box 230)
    - Riggs, Ricky, An Examination of Pietism and Its Impact Upon American Methodism, undated (Box 230)
    - Rives, Ralph Hardee, A Brief History of Littleton College, 1968 (Box 230)
    - Robertson, Florine, In His Train: A Brief Account of the Proceedings of the North Carolina Conference Woman's Society of Christian Service During the First Seven Years of Unification, 1949, 2 folders (Box 230)
      Typed manuscript. Includes photocopy of original cover. History covers about 40 pages; the rest, approx. 200 pages, consists of many one-page biographies of women in the Society, and a large number of newsletter extracts and photographs. "Written at the request of the Conference Historical Committee."
    - Rogal, Samuel, 5 folders (Box 231)
      Five articles: Women: Susanna Wesley and Her Daughters, 1981, 1982; Horace Walpole and the Methodists, undated; John Wesley and the Press-Gangs, 1975; John Wesley's Daily Routine, 1974; and John Wesley's Mission to Scotland, 1751-1790, 1988.
    - Ross, Brian R., Ralph Cecil Horner: A Methodist Sectarian Deposed, 1887-1895, 1976-1977 (Box 231)
    - Schneider, Gregory A., Perfection of the Family of God: Religious Community and Family Values in Early American Methodism, 1975 (Box 231)
    - Semmel, Bernard, Wesley's Economics, (circa 1971) (Box 231)
    - Semmens, Bernard L., Can We Get Methodist Origins Straight?, 1969-1970 (Box 231)
    - Shepherd, Victor, 'That We May Perfectly Love Thee,' John Wesley and Sanctification, 1988 (Box 231)
    - Shoaf, Cliff, John Wesley's Views on the Ministry, 1978 (Box 231)
    - Soppitt, Agnes Blair, A Silent Woman: A Farce in One Act, undated (Box 231)
    - Smith, Timothy, George Whitefield and Wesleyan Perfectionism, 1982-1983 (Box 231)
    - Smith, Timothy, John Wesley and the Second Blessing, 1986 (Box 231)
    - Stoker, David, 'Innumerable Letters of Good Consequence in History': The Discovery and First Publication of the Paston Letters, 1995 (Box 231)
    - Stookey, Laurence Hull, Charles Wesley: Mentor and Contributor to Liturgical Renewal, 1989 (Box 231)
    - Swift, Wesley F., How to Write a Local History of Methodism, 1964 (Box 231)
    - Tillyard, Frank, Distribution of Free Churches, 1935 (Box 231)
    - Tyson, John R., Charles Wesley: A Reader, 1986, 1988 [proof] (Box 231)
    - Waddington, George, Typescript copy of autobiography, undated (Box 231)
    - Walker, Albert, Wanted, A Wife!, undated (Box 231)
    - Wallace, Charles, Simple and Recollected: John Wesley's Lifestyle, 1977 (Box 231)
    - Walters, John R., Perfection in Ephesians' Salvation, Ethics, Eschatology, undated (Box 231)
    - Walters, Orville, The Concept of Attainment in John Wesley's Christian Perfection, 1971 (Box 231)
    - Walters, Stanley, Strange Fires: A Biblical Allusion in John Wesley's Hymns, 1978 (Box 231)
    - Watson, David, Accountable Discipleship, 1984 (Box 231)
    - Weber, Theodore, Political Order in Ordo Salutis: A Wesleyan Theory of Political Institutions, 1990 (Box 231)
    - Whited, Harold Vaughn, A Rhetorical Analysis of the Published Sermons Preached by John Wesley at Oxford University, 1958 (Box 232)
    - Wilkinson, Scott, Methodist Meeting Houses Visited by Thomas Mann, 1978 (Box 232)
    - Willimon, William H., Untitled, 1989 (Box 232)
    - Wise, Danny C., A History of Mt. Zion United Methodist Church, 1772-1975, 1975 (Box 232)
    - Wood, A. Skevington, John Wesley, Theologian of the Spirit, 1977 (Box 232)
    - Young, Carlton R., The Earliest USA Methodist Hymnals, 1992 (Box 232)
    - Unknown author: Full Salvation: A Descriptive Analysis of the Diary of Anna Reynalds in Truro, 1775-1840, undated (Box 232)
      Probably by Thomas R. Albin, author of the similar title "Full Salvation: The Spirituality of Anna Reynalds of Truro, 1775-1840," 1981.
    - Unknown author: John Wesley and Methodist Enthusiasm in Bristol, undated (Box 232)
    - Unknown author: John Nelson: A Study in Persecution, 1978 (Box 232)
    - Unknown author: Methodist Enthusiasm, undated (Box 232)
    - Unknown author: The Spiritual Pilgrimage of John Wesley: the Oxford Years, 1980 (Box 232)
    - Unpublished poems, plays, sketches and cameos by various authors, undated, 2 folders (Box 232)
  - Writings Series: Oversize Materials
    - Greeny Grass-Blade and the Rest (Hart 3,1938) (Box OV 6)
    - The Story of Methodism in Newland: Notes on Cottingham: population statistics and data (negative photo reproduction), 1851; and broadside reproductions, 1811, 1833, and 1871 (Box OV 6)
    - Other Publications, undated (Box OV 6)
    - The Story of Cleethorpes page proofs, circa 1953, 2 folders (Box OV 6)